KAVASKAR. M

Senior Engineer / Technical Lead

Kavaskarmatlab@gmail.com

9500514540

Versatile professional 4 years of experience as MATLAB Image Processing developer and 3 years of experience as System Engineer in Enterprise Architecture tool and 3 years of Product owner for magic draw tool customization to support model-based software & system Engineering and 8 months of experience in bridge between MATLAB & MAGICDRAW architecture model import & export development and as overall 10+ years contributed in complete SW development life cycle of digital image processing, SW detailed design and SW architecture analysis in automotive domain.

Professional Experience:

January 2020 - Present

Senior Engineer / Product Owner Renault Nissan Technology Business Centre India, Chennai

Magic draw tool plugin customizations for model-based system, software, and simulation architecture

Role: Product Owner and Lead Developer

Responsibilities: Owning tool customization, Leading the MATLAB and development activities, Interaction with different stakeholders and collect the requirements, requirements to feature conversion in JIRA, creating user stories and spikes, test cases creation in JIRA X-Ray, Functional validation and review of plugins, Implementing the Agile approach, and Release management.

Skillset and Tools: Core JAVA (JAVA 8), Magic Draw 2019 SP3 and Refresh-1 2021x, Enterprise Architect, Eclipse, MATLAB/SIMULINK, JIRA, GIT, UML, SysML.

Bridge between Magic draw and Different Architecture tool:

- Enterprise Architecture: Class Diagram, Sequence Diagram & Component Diagram Imported into MAGICDRAW using VB-script
- UPPAL: Import Plugin created in Magic draw to convert .xml to. mdxml format to use in MAGICDRAW
- MATLAB Import & Export from MAGICDRAW
 - M -Script .xml generate from MATLAB & Using script MATLAB model creation and bus editor file generation
 - Model Creation and analyse in MAGICDRAW and MATLAB.

March 2017 - December 2019

Senior Engineer KPIT, Bangalore

Enterprise Architecture - Model Design in ADAS

Role: Lead Designer

Responsibilities: Understand Requirement and model design in Enterprise architecture. Two weeks once with client improvement process will be described and sharing model to users.

Skillset and Tools: SysML Modelling Language, ADAS Concept (Features – ACC, LKAS, Front Camera Module)

Model Design in Enterprise Architecture: Use Case Diagram, Class Diagram, Sequence Diagram, Component Diagram, Block Diagram, and Internal Block Diagram.

April 2016 - February 2017

Software Engineer MAPLES Imaging Solution Pvt Ltd, Chennai

Real Time Character Recognition using OCR in Image Processing

Role: Project Developer

Responsibilities: To write Automation Script in MATLAB - Neural Network OCR Data base Image.

Skillset and Tools: MATLAB, M Script, Image Processing.

August 2012 - April 2016

Software Engineer Pantech Pro-Ed Pvt Ltd, Hyderabad and Chennai

Image Processing Projects
Role: Project Developer

Responsibilities: Analyse Image Processing IEEE Concepts and develop projects

Skillset and Tools: MATLAB, M Script, Image Processing.

Education:

June 2009 - April 2012

June 2007 - April 2009

June 2006 - April 2007

June 2004 - April 2005

B.E in ECE - 7.3 CGPA, Infant Jesus College of Engineering & Technology at Tuticorin, TN

Diploma in EEE - 76%, Arasan Ganesan Polytechnic College at Sivakasi, TN

HSC in Tamil - 62.5%, St. Xavier's Higher Secondary School at Tirunelveli, TN

SSLC in Tamil - 80.8%, St. Xavier's Higher Secondary School at Tirunelveli, TN

Key Skills

0	0	0	0	0	M Script in MATLAB		
0	0	0	0	0	Model Design in MATLAB		
0	0	0	0	0	UML/SysML		
0	0	0	0	0	Enterprise Architecture - Model Design and VB Script		
0	0	0	0	0	Magic Draw - Model Design , Analysis		
0	0	0	0	0	Magic Draw - Import & Export Plugin Develop in Core Java		
0	0	0	0	0	Machine Learning - SVM , Neural Network		
0	0	0	0	0	Image Processing		
0	0	0	0	0	GIT		